and in Italy If you read Jani radari
а в Италии Если вы читали Джани радари
Jani radari there is such a children's writer,
Джани радари есть такой детский писатель
you read it, I know I read it as a child, I
читали знаю читал в детстве я в
grew up in the Soviet Union Yes, Chipolino
Советском Союзе вырос Вот да Чиполино
There and so on stories he generally is
Там и так далее рассказы он вообще это
dating the war
датирования война
began That is, when when Chipolino
началась То есть когда когда Чиполино на
attacked Signor Tomato
Синьор помидора напал
yes hello yes  hello, I’m from the
да здравствуйте да здравствуйте Я из
city of Khmelnitsky, where do you
города Хмельницкий Вы откуда
know? We’ve already talked twice, even
ли зна к два раза уже общались даже
somewhere there was a recording for a long time, I haven’t
где-то была запись давно е с вами я не
talked to you for a long time Well, in any case, I’ve
общался Ну в любом случае я вас
already greeted you I know you, you’re
приветствовал уже Я знаю вас вы
Russian, I haven’t talked to you Well,
российский типа я с вами не общался Ну
yes you are  Do you think
да вы так считаете
Yes, we didn’t communicate with you, I didn’t communicate.
Да не общались с вами я не общался
The question is so interesting, look, you
Вопрос такой интересный смотрите Вы
saw Carlson’s interview with your
видели интервью Карлсона с вашим этим
Putin, I
Путиным
didn’t watch it in its entirety, yes. How do you feel
целиком не смотрел да Как вы относитесь
about the fact that Putin justifies Hitler in
к тому что Путин оправдывает Гитлера в
attacking Poland, he says that
нападении на Польшу говорит что это
Poland forced it because it was
Польша вынудила потому что была
intractable, to give up Gdansk?
несговорчивый отдать гданск
Putin said in an interview n yes Well,
это Путин рассказывал в интервью н да Ну
you see, I haven’t seen this, let’s just
я вот это видите не видел се давайте мы
listen now, I’ll
прослушал обязательно я
just No, let’s say that the president of
просто Нет давайте как вот президент
your country was
страны вашей
forced by the Poles, they forced them to play too hard
вынудили поляки вынудили они заигрались
and forced Hitler to start the Second World
и вынудили Гитлера начать Вторую Мировую
War with them. Why did the war start on
Войну именно с них Почему началась война
September 1st?  years, it was with Poland
1 сентября ри де года именно с Польшей
that it turned out to be no collusion; Hitler had
она оказалась не сговор Гитлеру ничего
no choice in implementing his plans
не оставалось при реализации его планов
to start with Poland; after all, they forced the
начать именно с Польши всё-таки вынудили
fields as a tract of the word
поля как тракту слова
read; I generally don’t agree with this idea; I’m
чит я вообще с этой идеей не согласен
generally surprised that Putin said this; I
вообще удивлён что это сказал это Путин
think Poland; Yes, intractable, this is
считаю Польшу Да несговорчивый это ВС
true.  but in general, the dating itself of the
верно но вообще сама по себе датировка
beginning of this
начала вот этой
war and Hitler’s actions It is more Well
войны и действий Гитлера Она более Ну
earlier No, look, look at the chronology, the
рань Нет смотрите смотри хронология
Second World War began on
чёткая Вторая Мировая Война началась 1
September 1 of this year, this has been going on for a
сентября ри дего года это несется
long time and the Hitler tribunal, this
давно и трибунал гитлеровский этот
Nuremberg was and historians are all clear about the date, you
нюрберг был и историки всё чётко дата вы
open now Wikipedia any
открываете сейчас Википедию любой
textbook by name Yes Andrey My name is
учебник по зовут Да Андрей Меня зовут
Andrey Yes look We open any
Андрей Да смотри Мы открываем любой
history textbook and Wait Andrey there
учебник по истории и Подождите Андрей
are at least three and in principle
существует как минимум три а в принципе
even five dated to the Second World
даже и пять датирована Второй мировой
War, once again the generally accepted dating
войны ещё раз всеми признанная датировка
is September 1, 1939 if I now
- это 1 сентября 1939 года если я сейчас
open a large Russian  encyclopedia of
открою большую российскую энциклопедию
lies world war It will be written
вра мировая война Там будет написано 1
September 1st of the year Well, okay, that
сентября де года Ну хорошо вас это
suits you If the date is such a date
устраивает Если дата дата такая у ме
Vozhe I have to answer then in your
Воже я должен ответить тогда в вашей
logic But I took you in another logic
логике Но вам отвел уже в другой логике
of my own, I’m no longer in yours I
своей кото меня больше я не в вашей Я
want it in logic  Putin understand that the
хочу вот в логике Путина понять что
president is for you to ask him Wait,
президент вам него спрашивать Подождите
you are a citizen of the Russian Federation, your
вы гражданин Российской Федерации ваш
president
президент
for the whole world, wait no I’m asking
на весь мир подождите нет Я спрашиваю у
you, maybe you have an opinion That is, I want to
вас может быть мнение То есть я хочу
hear from you Putin justifies
услышать от вас Путин оправдывает
Hitler, whether it works or not And in what
Гитлера получается или нет А в каки В
exact terms did he justify
каком именно выражении он здесь оправдал
Hitler here?  He said that Paul that Poland
Гитлера Он сказал что Поль что Польша
was not a collusion and therefore forced
была не сговор и поэтому вынудила
Hitler to attack. What does it mean that Poland
Гитлера напасть Что означает что Польша
forced Hitler? Yes Well then we must
вынудила Гитлера да Ну мы тогда должны
Consider with you this foreign and
Рассмотреть с вами эту внешнюю и
domestic policy of Poland in that period
внутреннюю политику Польши в тот период
and once again what does it mean that Poland
да ещё раз ещё раз что значит Польша
forced Hitler Napa who is to blame  in the
вынудила Гитлера Напа кто виноватый в
attack on Poland Poland or gi
нападении на Польшу Польша или ги
let's so I'm not at all to blame in this
давайте так я нет виноваты вообще в этой
situation those people who created this Well the
ситуации те люди которые создали эту Ну
situation itself this crisis in
саму ситуацию вот эту кризис в
Europe So who Let's So who is to blame
Европе Так кто Давайте Так кто виноват
there can be there can be counted
туда можно туда можно причислить в
first of all the British Americans stop
первую очередь англичан американцев стоп
stop no it's you  we’ve already made it up, let’s eat it this way
стоп нет это вы уже выдумали давайте так
clearly Yes, and the Nyurba tribe,
есть чётко Да и нюрбинский триб моё
see my opinion Andrey, interrupt You
мнение смотрите Андрей перебивайте Вы
want my opinion to be the same
хотите чтобы моё мнение было такое же
as
как
not I want to ask your opinion
не я хочу спросить ваше мнение
differs from the official opinion of all
отличается от официального мнения всех
countries and which, the winner of the
стран да которых победителе
anti-Hitler coalition,
антигитлеровской коалиции
you seem to be a serious blogger who has been here for a long time
даре вы вроде бы серьёзный блогер давно
[music] the
[музыка]
opinion of all countries will be present
присут мнение всех стран
again
опять
proto I want to understand
прото Я хочу понять
it is connected with the position that
она связана с позицией которую в своё
Stalin also supported at one time because at
время поддержал тоже Сталин потому что в
that moment it was beneficial with the
тот момент это было выгодно с той
position that was beneficial to the British and
позицией которая выгодна англичанам и
Americans and partly the French But
американцам и частично французам А
actually this is not just this  one of the
вообще-то это не одна это одна из
free Mita
даровой Мита
has children writers know I read it as a child
есть детй писатели знаю читал в детстве
I grew up in the Soviet Union So Dalen
я в Советском Союзе вырос Вот И дален
generally granted it When the war began in Spain,
вообще это даровал Когда в Испании война
when Lina attacked the Blue Tomato
началась то когда Лина на Синь помидора
Well, there was a tsa lemon
Да ну там е был ца лимон
coire you are now telling us in all seriousness
койре вы сейчас нам на полном серьёзе
thinker other Polina I'm talking about that I'm
мыслителя прочи Полина Я говорю о том Я
talking about the fact that there are several
говорю о том что Существует несколько
different and not just one dating
разных а не одна единственная датировка
look there is World War II
смотрите существует Второй мировой войны
look
смотрите
There are several different views on the
Существует несколько разных взглядов на
earth someone says that the Earth is flat
землю кто-то говорит что Земля плоская
Yes but there is an officially established
Да но есть официально установленная
position Yes that the Earth has not  flat
позиция Да что Земля имеет не плоскую
shape and the same thing, you want to talk about it
форму да то же само хоти об этом
about this example,
поговорить об этом приме гово
for example, you can consider that the Second
вы например можете считать что Вторая
World War began during the
Мировая Война началась во врем во
Neolithic times, and someone may believe
времена неолита да кто-то может считать
that the Second World War began with
что Вторая Мировая Война началась пи с
letters from Bogdan Don’t Wait for Jani radars
писем Богдана не Подождите Джани радари
Here’s an example  - then Jani Radari can
Вот например какой-то Джани радари может
write that the Second World War
написать что Вторая Мировая Война
began with the letters of Bogdan Khmelnitsky. For
началась с писем Богдана Хмельницкого Я
example, I say, look at Jani
например говорю смотрите вопрос Джани
Radari’s question again Astrid
радари ещё раз Астрид
Lynn The Grim Brothers, yes, that’s all who wrote the
Линн Братья Грим да все вот кто писали
fairy tales, they were very good men and
сказки они очень хорошие мужики были и
women Yes, but they do not determine the date of the
женщины Да но не они определяют дату
beginning of the Second World War  wars And who
начала Второй Мировой войны А кто
determines who determines That’s the
определяет кто определяет Вот
question, so let’s do it again Andrey And
вопрос так вот Давайте ещё раз Андрей А
I said earlier a phrase that you may
я ранее Сказал фразу которую возможно вы
have heard that this particular date
прослушали что данная вот эта дата о
that you’re talking about has gone down in history
которой вы говорите она вошла в историю
taking into account the interests of the British and the
с учётом интересов англичан и
Americans, this is the basis on which you
американских это на основании чего вы
say this I  I’ve already said this, the basis of
такое говорите я уже об этом сказал осно
what you’re
чего вы это
saying is based on your opinion about the
говорите на основании своего мнения про
British, everything That is, you’re not historians, we
англичани всё То есть вы это не историки
won’t
не
water it down, I understood everything, that’s it, that’s it, you
полим всё понял то так гово то Вы меня
’re asking me for my opinion,
спрашиваете моё мнение
nanny, no, I’m looking, I’m The thing is, I didn’t
няня не я смотрите я Дело в том что не
ask your opinion, I thought  you asked
спросил ваше мнение Я думал спросите вы
me specifically and asked in my No No
именно меня и спросили в мою Нет Нет
look I when I clarified about the date of the start of the First
смотрите Я когда про дату начала Первой
World War or do you understand
мировой войны я уточнил или вы понима
your personal you are a historian by
ваша личная вы историк по
education a historian by
образовани историк по
education I am not a historian by education and
образовани я по образованию не историк и
I am not a historian Yes, but there are people who are historians by
я не историк Да но есть люди историки по
education  people
образованию есть люди
who, by my second education and by my
которые я по второму образованию по
first, are a programmer, but I’m not a historian Yes, I
первому программист но я не историк Да я
rely
опираюсь
on the documents of historians and those people, where the hell did he
на документы историков и тех людей блин
run away
куда убежал
Oh, they’re so fried, they’re spinning like snakes in a
Ой прожарок как крутятся как ужи на
frying pan Yes, Putin, but I have another one,
сковородке Да Путин но я имею другую не
I’m not interested in how you evaluate what
мне интересно как ты оцениваешь то что
Putin
Путин
Yes justified
Да оправдал
Hitler the British the French can be
Гитлера англичане французы можно
moved let's move it in short
сдвинуть давайте давайте сдвинем короче
once Jani radar who wrote
когда-то Джани радари который написал чи
Polina's chi I haven't heard this yet damn it
Полина такого я ещё не
for chi Polina put Donat on the
блин за чи Полина закиньте Донат на
channel Here San is your
канал Вот Сань это твой
passenger Come on
пассажир Давай са
here San won't give here sa sanyaba
сюда Сань не будет сюда давать са саняба
Come on come here he  a negative person is not a
Давай иди сюда он негативный человек не
negative person blogger Sanya
он негативный человек блогер Саня давай
come here Hello Sanya is already in good condition
иди сюда Здра о Саня уже в кондиции
I’m from the city of Khmelnitsk Where are you from Sanya
Я из города Хмельницке Вы откуда Саня
Moscow Moscow Did you come to Moscow or were you
Москва Москва А вы приехали в Москву или
born in Moscow came And where did
родились в Москве приехали А откуда
Sanya come from to Moscow
приехали Саня в московье
specifically Pushkina I know Pushkina
конкретней Пушкина о знаю Пушкина
Ivanteevka we know these  Dada over there
Ивантеевка знаем такие Дада вон
Ivanteevsky is sitting about Ivanteevka Come on
Ивантеевский сидит о Ивантеевка Давайте
Krasava So what are you talking about Sanya here about
Красава Так о чём общаешься Саня тут обо
everything What the interlocutor will talk about VM
всём О чём собеседник будет говорить ВМ
once and Ivanka You’ve been there no thank
раз а Иванка Вот вы бывали там нет слава
God you haven’t
Богу не
been
бывал
where you know that Ivanteevka is not far from
гда знае что Ивантеевка недалеко от
Pushkin and Pushkin have been no thank God have
Пушкина а Пушкина бывали не слава Богу
n’t been A  where do you know you know that
не бывал А откуда знаете зна знае что
Pushkin is not far from Ivanteevka and Tishchi is
Пушкина недалеко от Ивантеевки и тищ
not far from the bushes and
недалеко от пуш и
cows, look at who you work
коров смотрите кем работаете
guys so Yes,
пацаны так Да
what kind of [ __ ] do you work
какую гою работаете
and who do you work Yes, the
а кем работаем Да
municipality, more specifically, the wipers, well, you can
муниципал конкретнее дворники ну можно
say, we manage the
так сказать управляем
wipers And more specifically, how do you
дворниками А конкретнее как это
manage the wipers, so that the area
управляете дворниками ну чтобы на районе
is clean
была чистота
I understand it’s true that they say that like, I
Поня это правда говорят что типа вот я
saw a report that there are already wipers
видел репортаж что с кубы уже дворников
from Cuba. Yes, they actually recruited 3,000 from Cuba to Moscow from Cuba.
из Кубы реально да Да уж привезли 3.000
Well, I saw that there weren’t enough
Ну я видел да что не хватает что
Cubans, like there was already a photo
кубинцев типа уже было фото
video report that the Cubans were stranded there. And this is
видеорепортаж что кубинцы там мели А это
what will happen  populate I didn’t hear
то что будут заселять Это не слышал
the village, of course the collective farms will raise
деревня конечно будут колхозы подымать
the cubes And that the Russians can’t raise
куби А что русские не могут поднять
the collective farm, apparently they can’t And that the Russians,
колхоз видимо не могут А что у русских
like the hands of the carcass, can’t raise the collective farm
типа руки туше не могут колхоз поднять
no, everything grows where it needs to Well why For
нет всё растёт где надо Ну почему
example,
Например
in Holland, farmers can cultivate the
в Голландии фермеры могут обрабатывать
land Yes, they don’t need to bring  Cubans
землю Да им не нужно привозить кубинцев
to cultivate the land, and the Russians need to
чтобы обработать землю а русским нужно
bring Cubans. Well, they want us to come
кубинцев привозить Ну хотят нам приехать
to you then, a counter question: Why
тогда к вам встречный вопрос А почему
can the Ukrainians
украинцы могут
cultivate land that is not theirs, which has already
обрабатывать не свою землю которую уже
become not their Land? How can you
всё стала не их Земля Это как так
understand it? Just say that there are hundreds of Lands,
понять е раз скажи что там ста Земля об
you have citizens Yes  who can
есть у вас граждане Да которые могут
cultivate
обрабатывать
the land
землю
correctly and manage the farm Well,
правильно вести хозяйство Ну вести
they can manage the fields correctly
хозяйство же Могут могут правильно поля
That is, everything is supposed to be cultivated,
Вот то есть обрабатывать всё полагается
but you don’t have any fields of
но у вас полей в Украине не осталось
your own in Ukraine. Where did the land
своей А куда делась Земля Америка всё
go? America took everything under its own control.
взяла под свой оборот
Yeah, it turns out interesting, we don’t have
Ага интересность получается у нас нету
ownership of the land there  and there
собственности на землю там и аренды там
is no rent there, in short, it’s all in America Yes, everything is
нет короче всё это в Америке Да всё
correct, but where did you hear that and
правильно а а где ты такою услышал да
where everything is in the public domain, read Where
где всё в открытом доступе почитайте Где
in the public domain, okay Now I’ll read it,
в открытом доступе ладно Сейчас почитаю
let me
давай мне
wonder what his name is, ask me, you’re
интересно как его зовут спроси ня с
talking to a person, you don’t know his name, what’s
человеком общаешься не знаешь как его
your name?  name is Andrey Vasilyevich
зовут Как вас зовут Андрей Васильевич
Very nice Alexander
Очень приятно Александр
Petrovich Let's sanyaba now Find Like
Петрович Давай саняба сейчас Найди Как
Americans Which corporations now VS we'll
американцы Какие корпорации сейчас ВС
tell
расскажем
Zavra tsm district village of Kruti Brody now I'm
Завра цм районе село крути Броды вот я
already looking like Elon Musk I think I want to
уже смотрю как илон Маск дума я хочу
buy a vegetable garden in Krutye Brody ha
огород в Крутых бродах купить ха
zabrodi need to
заброди надо
E let's get this information
Э давайте вот вам это информационный
portal con  I inform you that, according to information from the
портал кон сообщаю что по информации
Australian
австралийско
national corporation, they bought 17 million
национальной корпорации купили 17 млн
hectares of Ukrainian agricultural
гектаров украинских сельскохозяйственных
land, for comparison, this area in
угодий для сравнения эта площадь на
Ukraine is more useful
Украине боль больше и полезной
agricultural land than all of
сельскохозяйственной земли как всей
Italy. So now look, I
Италии Так теперь смотри я правильно
understand correctly that some leftist site, referring
понимаю что какой-то левый сайт ссылаясь
to an Australian site, said that the
на австралийский сайт сказал что
Australian site wrote  that
австралийский сайт написал что
American companies bought something in
американские компании что-то скупили в
Ukraine Well, that’s right And there is a shorter
Украине так Ну правильно А есть покороче
chain of sources
цепочка источников
Andrey
Андрей
Vasilyevich, pay attention
Васильевич внима
exactly what kind of
именно что это за
American companies these are, by the
компаний американс
way, we had a lot of moratoriums on
у нас кстати было много мораторий на
agricultural land, and before that,
сельскохозяйственную землю а до этого и
land could be sold anyway. Yes, not for
так землю можно было продавать Да не
agricultural purposes, let’s do
сельскохозяйственного назначения давай
this  what’s bad about that, yes That the Earth
так что плохого в том да Что у Земли
can have an owner, including a
может быть собственник в том числе и
foreign one Well, tell me, I’m asking you
иностранный Ну скажите я вас спрашиваю В
What’s bad, for example, if an
чём плохого вот например если если
investor Yes comes, what’s bad, I don’t
инвестор Да приходит в чём плохого я не
know Tell me please Well,
знаю Скажите пожалуйста Ну вот у тебя
how much land do you have?  2 over the
сколько у тебя земли есть у тебя 2 над
demon
бес
everything, that is, I understand that you don’t have
всё то есть я понимаю что у тебя нет
any land plot. Yes, no,
никакого земельного участка Да нет
of course you do. What kind of land
конечно же есть Какой у тебя земельный
plot do you have? And how much it turns out, I don’t know how
участок так А сколько получается не знаю
many acres there are, I’ll now tell you how much
сколько соток там я сейчас скажу сколько
I have, approximately now I’ll go right in, about
у меня примеро сейчас зайду пря порядка
thirty acres and no, not  thirty is
тридцати соток и нет не тридцати
probably already twenty-two acres and plus
наверное уже двадцати двух соток и плюс
at the dacha it’s a garden, let’s
на даче это сад
go, that is, look, I
поехали то есть смотри я правильно
understand correctly that you don’t have a farmer’s field,
понимаю что поля фермерского у тебя нет
you have a dacha
у тебя есть дача
dacha and plus to it Well, it’s not a farmer’s
дача и плюс ко нему Ну не фермерское
field, just like that, what do you think?
поле такое вот неболь как как ты думаешь
The Americans bought up all the dachas in  Ukraine
Американцы скупили все дачи в Украине
or not Hear Umenya plot 2000 m skoko
или нет Слыш Уменя участк 2000 м скоко
m Vasil all the best to you goodbye
м Василь всего хорошего вам до свидания
where is he running away not for us to go We need to go
куда убегает не нам ехать Надо ехать
no no Let's talk It's interesting we
надо не не Давайте поговорим Интересно
communicate normally
нормально же общаемся
everything will remain Sanya we are now dozha Yes
остатся всё всё Саню мы сейчас дожа Да
look Sanya That is, I understand correctly I
смотри Саня То есть я правильно я
understand correctly  that you have
правильно понимаю что у тебя есть
a dacha then the link to the skete channel is called
дача потом ссылку ските канал называется
Andriy popk the channel Andriy popk is called
Андрий попк канал Андрий попк называется
look Sanya I understand correctly that the
смотри Саня я правильно понимаю что у
Americans did not buy your dacha from you
тебя американцы не выкупили твою дачу у
you have a dacha With a
тебя есть дача С
vegetable garden E no no So in Ukraine the
огородик Е нет нет Так а в Украине
Americans bought up the dachas with
американцы у всех скупили дачи с
vegetable gardens for ladies
огородами дам
I read that now for a second everything la
прочитал то что сейчас секунду всё ла
Let's dial let's dial
Давай наберём давай набирайте
[music]
[музыка]
tomorrow that The boys went to
завтра что Пацаны пошли
sweep the farmland Yes,
подметать сельскохозяйственные угодия Да
Alexander you have farmland in your possessions
у тебя Александр есть во владениях
in
сельскохозяйственные угодия в
Russia No no no
России Нет нету нету
you don't have farmlands in your possessions
что у тебя нет во владениях
Just like your buddies don't have
сельскохозяйственных угодий Как нету у
them Yes  but you’re worried
твоих этих корешей Да но ты переживаешь
that
что что-то в Украине
someone bought agricultural land in Ukraine.
сельскохозяйственные угодия кто-то
Why am I not saying that I’m
выкупил Да почему я не говорю что я
worried? I’m just saying. I’m stating
переживаю Я просто говорю Констатирую
a fact like this. Why don’t you buy agricultural land in your country?
факт так А почему ты у себя в стране не
Alexander, why why, for the
Александр зачем зачем вот вот вот по
same reason?  I don’t buy
этой же причине я не покупаю
agricultural land, for example,
сельскохозяйственные угодия например
spruce Yes, some kind of agricultural corporation, ours or a
ели Да какой-то агрокорпорация нашей или
foreign one, is necessary. They buy, they
иностранной нужно Они покупают они
invest because they are engaged in
инвестируют потому что они занимаются
this
этим
business,
бизнесом
yes, that is, for me specifically, I can buy
да то есть мне конкретно я могу покупать
land, in short, the boys came in and
землю короче зашли пацаны
looked in a second, there are 5,000 but 5,000
смотрят сечас секун там 5000 но 5000
looks Yes, look, that is  if I don’t
смотрит Да смотри То есть если мне не
need it I can, as a citizen of Ukraine,
нужно Я могу как гражданин Украины
buy land plots Yes, but I do
покупать земельные участки Да но мне они
n’t need them because I’m doing something
не нужны потому что я занимаюсь чем-то
else Yes, I don’t need to invest
другим Да вот мне не нужно инвестировать
my money there and I’m a programmer and a
свои деньги туда инима я программист а
programmer Yes, that is, if for example
программист Да вот то есть если например
you work in a rural  in the economy yes
ты работаешь в сельском хозяйстве да
You need this and then you participate in this market
Тебе нужно это и ты тогда в этом рынке
I don’t need why it
участвуешь мне не нужно зачем это меня
would bind me more
более связывало бы да
and you don’t need it either but you
так же и тебе не нужно но ты что-то
read something somewhere that in Ukraine America
где-то прочитал что в Украине Америка
was bought out they constantly talk about it and
выкупалась постоянно об этом говорят а
so Why  they tell you about this all the time
так А зачем вам постоянно об этом
And why do you need me
говорят И зачем тебе
just like that You see, this is what
это я просто вот Понимаете вот что мне
catches my eye I read I read I read
на глаза попадает я читаю Читаю читаю
when the same thing comes across I
когда одно и тоже попадается вот всё
understand everything, that is, you just read it and it
понял то есть ты просто вот так чту да
caught your eye and you read it
на глаза попалось и ты читаешь на глаза
caught your eye You read Yes  And if you
попалось Читаешь Да А у вас если наг
come across something naked, you don’t read, I choose what to
попадается вы не читаете я я выбираю что
read. It’s clear. Well, it was written there.
читать Понятно Ну это в тхе было
Yes, sometimes I come in and see what you’re reading. You
Да иногда захожу смотрю читаешь Ты
read rubbish and what you
читаешь труху а что
don’t understand. Do you have any other questions?
нет понял У вас ещё какие-то вопросы
Yes, in principle, I don’t even know
есть Да у меня в принципе я даже не знаю
And probably what else
А наверное что ещё
uh Maybe you have something Ask me a question Oh
ээ Может у вас что Задайте мне вопрос А
well,
ладно
what do you think, this will still
этот как считаете всё-таки
be the same as before Ukraine will be the fraternal
будет как раньше Украина будет братским
people
народом
of Russia, this is a very serious question, you ca
России это очень серьёзный вопрос на
n’t answer it without laughing What kind of fraternal
него без ржач не ответишь Какие братские
peoples dude Look what fraternal
народы чувак Смотри какие братские
peoples we have, explain, explain  look
народы у нас объясняй объясняю смотри
America America bought all the land from us. Of
Америка Америка у нас выкупила всю землю
course we would like it to.
Мы конечно мы хотели бы да чтобы
Despite the fact that Russia is bombing us with so many of our
Несмотря на то что Россия столько наших
people. We want to be
людей бомбит нас Мы хотим снова быть
fraternal peoples again, but evil America
братскими народами но злая Америка
bought our Earth and they say: If you
выкупила нашу Землю и говорят Если вы
are fraternal peoples with Russia, we will
будете братские народы с Россией мы
take your land  will dig up the black soil and
заберём вашу землю выкопает чернозём и
take it to the state of Colorado, you understand,
увезём в штат Колорадо понимаешь
we want to be fraternal peoples, we want to,
мы хотим быть братскими народами хотим
but America won’t let you, you don’t want to attack
но не даёт амери вы ж не хотите напасть
America.
на Америку
Why did you
Почему вы напали на нас на Братский
attack us?
Америка перестала выкупать нашу Землю
look if you're reading Wait, you know
смотри если ты читаешь Подожди ты знаешь
You know that America is buying back our
Вы знаете что Америка выкупает нашу
Earth and instead of helping us
Землю и вместо того чтобы помочь нам
buy this land back, you bomb us,
выкупить эту землю назад вы бомби нас
build on the basis that this is a response
строи на основании того что это ответный
in case of an attack by nuclear weapons to the
в случае нападения ядерного оружия в
side. So why not attack by ships
сторону Так почему не напад кораблями
with missiles on
ракетами на
America?
Америку
Why  why don’t
Почему почему не
yours tell you to go to Cuba? In short,
скажут ваши на Кубу Короче
why watch How the Americans are buying back
почему смотрите Как американцы выкупают
the land from the Brotherly people and didn’t
у Братского народа землю и не выку
squeeze the poto pun,
зажали пото пун
you betrayed our Brotherly people, you
вы предали наш Братский народ вы
allowed the Americans to buy back
позволили американцам выкупить выкупить
everything because it was important for you
всё потому что сами что вам важно было
to make the Olympics in Sochi instead of
Олимпиаду сделать в Сочи вместо того
taking it and buying it back  land Here the
чтобы взять и выкупить земли Тут у
Americans took it from the Americans and bought it. But
Американ американцы взяли и выкупили А
you couldn’t take it and buy it, yachts,
вы вы не могли взять и выкупить яхты
yachts, you’re buying the Olympics, yes, but
яхты покупаете Олимпиаду делаете Да а
take it and buy it back. If you don’t want to take it from the Americans, take it from the
взять выкупить Землю Не хотите у
Americans. Brotherly
американцев так возьмите Братского
people, you’ll buy the Americans land and
народа вы купите американцев землю и
give it away. Why is it the most interesting
Отдайте Почему самые интересно потому
because you sit all day reading?  Damn
что ты сидишь целыми днями читаешь блин
Telegram, instead of going out and
Telegram вместо того чтобы выйти и
saying Putin, you buy the Americans land
сказать Путин вы купи американцев землю
for the Brotherly people Why will it
для Братского народа Почему бесплатно
go to us for free? You understand Why won’t the
нам отойдёт понимаете Почему вы так
Americans give up their land that was
американцы не отдадут свою землю
bought back You can’t seize everything,
выкуплен ную Всё вы не сможете захватить
no no, the Americans bought it Why did
нет нет американцы выкупили Почему
Carlson come to Putin He conveyed
Карлсон приезжал к Путину Он передал
Trump’s message everything  dude,
трампа послание всё чувак там
all the agricultural lands there were bought
сельскохозяйственные земли все выкуплены
by America, these are American lands, you
Америкой это американские земли
know, this is American Read
понимаешь это американский Прочитай
said, look, there is a site, go to the site, trash
сказал смотри есть сайт зайди сайт труха
with a link to an Australian source Yes,
с ссылкой на австралийский источник Да
who quoted a New Zealand
который цитировал новозеландского
politician Yes In which the
политика Да Во которому это лично
President of Brazil personally told this, he said that the
рассказал президент Бразилии сказал что
Americans bought the land specifically
американцы выкупили специально землю
so that Russia could not seize  it
чтобы Россия не могла захватить её
because this is the territory of America
потому что это территория Америки
Hello hello let's
здравствуйте давайте
talk You're
поговорим Вы
from where We're from Where
откуда Мы Откуда
we're from Eastern
мы Восточная
Siberia
Сибири
more specifically more specifically
конкретнее конкретне
Irkutsk I understand my dad served in
Иркутск понял у меня батя служил в
Irkutsk about the Trans-Baikal
Иркутской об Забайкальском
Territory
крае
good damn How do I know which part
хорошо блин Откуда я знаю в какой части
I haven't
меня ещё не
been to yet Let me myself I'm from
было Давай я сам я из
Almaty Almaty
Алматы Алматы
Almaty  Almaty That’s exactly where you are now. What are you
Алматы Алматы Вот именно вы сейчас здесь
doing? I’m communicating with Russians. I
занимаетесь общаюсь с россиянами вот я
see some Russian politicians
смотрю некоторые российские политики
are saying that the North of Kazakhstan should be
заявляют что Север Казахстана нужно
taken away by Russia because
забрать России потому что там
Russian-speaking people live there. Okay,
русскоязычные люди живут Хорошо давайте
let’s go on about how you feel about this.
давайте дальше об Как вы к этому
Why do I feel about this? Of course I’m
относитесь Почему к этому отношусь
against it, not against it, but
конечно против не против А
critically  critically, of course, because
критически критически конечно потому что
firstly, Kazakhstan grew this whole
во-первых Казахстан выращивал это всё
SSR, you don’t know about it
ССР вы об этом не
no Explain no no Okay, I wo
знаете нет Объясните нет нет Ладно
n’t explain,
объяснять не
you can ask the next one, but the
буду можете у следующего спросить но
fact is
дело в том то
that there will be another war then I mean,
что будет ещё одна война тогда В смысле
then you
тогда
will agree yes you want this
будет согласен да вы хотите эту
war  so this is what you want, you are now
войну так это вы хотите вы же сейчас
asking about this,
спрашиваете насчёт этого
about this, look, Kazakhstan
насчёт этого вот смотрите Казахстан
is grown, it’s all the USSR, first of all, what
выращено это всё ССР во-первых Что
does it mean, everything is grown? I don’t
значит выращено всё Это не
understand In the literal sense, what was grown by
понял В прямом смысле что выращено
the USSR, well ask the old
СССР хорошо спросите у старых
people what to
людей что
ask ask you understand about the World Cup
спросить спросите вы понимаете о ЧМ
ask I don’t
спроси не
understand  you don’t understand who was raised in the USSR I
понимаю не понимаете кто выращен на СССР
can’t understand about the World Cup you hands you are from
не могу понять о ЧМ вы руки вы сами из
Kazakhstan Yes
Казахстана Да
Almaaty Yes Almaaty Almaaty So what will
Алмааты Да Алмааты Алмааты Вот и там
happen in
будет в
Almaaty in
Алмааты в
Almaaty what will happen yes
Алмааты что будет да
you call us that Russians
ты вы что нас так называете русские
because
потому что
So why do you call us Kazakhs
Так а зачем ты нас казахов
on  in fact, it was the
называешь на самом деле Вот именно
Kazakhs who were raised raised in the SSR in the SSR
казахов вырастили вырастили в ССР в ССР
this all rose this all rose
это всё поднялось это всё поднялось это
isn’t it true nuka rose what
разве неправда нука поднялось что
rose in s rose this all everything
поднялось в с поднялось это вс всё
rose how much genocide of the Kazakhs
поднялось сколько геноцида казахов
was done by the Soviet Union famine in
сделано советским союзом голодомор в
Kazakhstan and
Казахстане да
your and our our
интеллигенции вашей и нашей нашей
Kazakh intelligentsia Me too now  I’ll
казахской Я тоже сейчас чая
drink some tea, what are you
попью что вы нас
calling us? Yes, because you don’t understand. This
называете Да потому что не понимаете Это
means that the person doesn’t
имеется в виду то то что человек не
understand. He doesn’t understand what he’s
понимает Не понимает что
saying among the Russians.
говорит среди русских есть
republics Yes, and what other 13
другие 14 республик Да и какие другие 13
fed Russia fed Moscow we
кормили Россию кормили Москву мы
built everything for you together with the republics
построили вам всё вместе с республиками
Baikal-Amur Mainline that you
Байкал амурскую магистраль что вы
built well again once again my
построили ну-ка ещё раз ещё раз мой мой
my father went as a student Baikalo-Amur
мой отец ездил студентом байкалоамурскую
Mainline is building built built Baikal-
магистраль строит построил Байкал
Amur Mainline Tsey on Shushenskaya demon
амурскую магистраль цея на Шушенской бес
we will build for you  wait, well, once again
мы вам построи подожди ну-ка ещё раз
about Baikal, my dad built the
насчёт Байкала мой батя строил
Baikalo-Amur highway bam their
байкалоамурскую магистраль бам их
students took them there and for free you
студентами возили туда да бесплатно вам
Russians for a second on bam they called him
русским секунду на на бам его позвали
first of all
во-первых его
he was called sog he didn’t build the Russians built
позвали сог он строил не русские строили
We Kazakhs Estonians Ukrainians Moldovans
Мы казахи эстонцы украинцы молдаване
built for you all
строили вам все
we built everything  you ruined your ru after
мы всё строили вам ру вы развалили после
we separated from you, you have
того как мы от вас отделились вы ничего
n’t built anything new in 30 years,
за 30 лет нового не построили
nothing is all that was there. Under the Soviet Union,
ничего всё что было При Советском Союзе
all 14 republics did it for you, Russia, and
это все 14 республик вам делали России
oil, gas, gold, we extracted everything, we
да нефть газ золото всё добывали мы
built
построили вам
everything for you, let’s
всё давай давай по
pump out resources and that’s it  what you Russians
выкачивали ресурсов и всё что вы русские
can do what you have done without Kazakhstan Ukraine
можете что вы без Казахстана Украины
Estonia Latvia in 30 years
Эстонии Латвии сделали за 30 леткой Ты
Who are we when we were yes we
кто такой мы когда мы были да мы
launched a man into space Baikanur
запустили человека в космос байканур
Look Baikanur we have
Смотри байканур это у нас в Казахстане
the sun behind you in Kazakhstan behind you of course they will
сзади тебя солнце сзади тебя конечно
come up and they will also take me
подойдут и и тоже возьмут возьмут меня
maybe
может
be it doesn’t matter It doesn’t matter what they
быть это неважно Это неважно что они там
do there but look, we have the Kazakhs
сделают но дело смотри у нас у казахов
have the Baikanur cosmodrome You have
есть космодром байканур У вас есть
such a level of cosmodrome Baikanur You know
такого уровня кос байканур Ты знаешь
Therefore, what does our
Поэтому что означает это ж наше
Kazakh word Baikanur mean Okay good good
казахское слово байканур Ладно хорошо
good You
хорошо Ты же
Justify why the Russian people needed Baikanur
Обоснуй Зачем байканур нужен был русским
I will say because
людям я скажу потому что
yes, you exploited us, Kazakhs,
да вы эксплуатировали нас казахов
Ukrainians, Moldovans, all of you. You can’t even
украинцев молдован всех Ты даже не
justify why all this is needed,
можешь обосновать для чего это всё нужно
and moreover, nuclear tests in
и больше того ядерные испытания в
Semipalatinsk. Who did it? Yes, how many
Семипалатинске Кто делал Да сколько
Kazakhs died because of this? What latitude,
казахов погибло из-за этого Какая широта
tell me what latitude is you? You
скажи какая тебе широта Ты математику
don’t even know mathematics  he will
даже не знаешь широту он будет
ask for latitude, look, we brought it When
спрашивать ты посмотри мы принесли Когда
you didn’t have Moscow, yes, we already had the
у вас Москвы не было да у нас была уже
Great Golden Horde, this is We were Kazakhs,
Великая Золотая Орда это Мы казахи были
yes,
да вы да
yes, and you’re sitting there talking to us with such
ла ещ и сидишь говоришь на нас такими
bad
плохими
words. Yes, no, I really
словами Да нет нет я на самом деле хочу
want to say that  that
хочу сказать то что вот
you have very good people, there are
именно у вас очень хорошие люди есть
very good women, there is all this very
очень хорошие женщины есть всё это очень
good, but you are exactly you, I repent, I
хорошо но вы вот именно вы вы я покамись
also call you you because you are nothing
ещ вас называю вы потому что вы е ничего
M
М
Speak, you are trying to
Говори вы пытаетесь
get a lot of people to
выйти на на то чтобы вас много
look at you Well, actually  no you are no one at all
смотрело Ну на самом деле нет вы вообще
I am not I No I don’t have anything
никто Я нет я Нет у меня нет ничего
like that
такого
no the Kazakhs have good people there are very
нет казахам хорошие люди есть очень
good people
хорошие люди
well in the USSR
хорошо в СССР
Kazakhstan built everything together with other
Казахстан строил вместе с другими
republics Or is it Russia that built everything for us
республиками всё Или это Россия Нам всё
in fact Russia
построила на самом деле Россия больше
built more but the Kazakhs of course they
строила но казахи конечно же они
brought it to  it’s all no, it was all all
приносили в это всё нет это всё всё было
together, the Kazakhs supported Russia or
вместе то казахи содержали России или
Russia contained the Kaz In short, you did
Россия содержала каза Короче говоря ты
n’t go Well, explain to me, look
пошёл не Ну объясни мне вот смотри
Why when we why when all
Почему когда мы почему когда все
the Republics of Russia separated from you you
Республики от вас России отделились вы
couldn’t
ничего не смогли
build anything, let’s not talk about this anymore,
построить давайте уже не будем об этом
you Well  Yes, look, 30 years Yes, you are
вы Ну да вот смотри 30 лет Да вы
Independent, your Yeltsin destroyed the
Независимый ваш Ельцин развалил
Soviet Union Yes, you made at least
Советский Союз Да что вы сделали хоть
one new nuclear power plant Yes, not a
одну атомную станцию новую Да не
Soviet one, you built at least one, uh,
совковую построили хоть короче один ээ
some kind of normal launch, you made it into
какой-то запуск нормальный сделали в
space, all Soviet technologies that
космос всё советские технологии которые
We are Kazakhs, Ukrainians, all of you yes Question
Мы казахи украинцы все вам да Вопрос
question  but it’s all the
вопрос к это же это же всё
same Okay good
равно Ладно хорошо
Uh-huh Yes, [ __ ] you, you
Угу Да пошёл ты
know, and you Russians will give Irkutsk to
знаешь и вы русские дате Иркутск дашь
Irkutsk These are not your Russian lands,
Иркутск Это же не ваши русские земли это
you came there, you are alien
вы пришли туда вы пришлые
conquerors there, the lands of the Turks and Arats of the
завоеватели там земли тюрков и аратов
Mongols, Lake Baikal is a Jurassic
монголов озеро Байкал это юрское
name
название
Tell me what Baikal means
Скажи что означает Байкал
everything  this is what
всё вот это его
undermined him, it’s just someone
подорвало жесть просто какой-то вот кто
from Kazakhstan Yes, this is the face of all these
из Казахстана Да вот это лицо всех этих
Russians Yes, they are with the same zeal as they are
русских Да они с таким же рвением как
ready to destroy Ukraine, they
готовы уничтожить Украину они также без
will also yell without any remorse Putin will
всякого зазрения будут орать Путин
give Tanks to Kazakhstan so that
давать Танки на Казахстан так
’s why all this cotton wool in their  countries
поэтому всю вот эту вату в своих странах
need to burn out hot iron and very,
нужно выжигать калёный железом и причём
very quickly
очень-очень быстро
hello Yes Good evening where are you
здравствуйте Да Добрый вечер вы откуда
from
из
Russia Yes I'm from Russia
России Да я из России
where I'm from
откуда я с
Yamal
Ямала
from Yamal island Yama Yamala Nenets
откуда С Ямала остров яма Ямала Ненецкий
Autonomous Okrug
округ автономный автоном
Sarajevo Sarajevo Sarajevo Bosnia and
сараево сараево Сараева Босния и
Herzegovina Herzegovina Yes, just now I
Герцеговина Герцеговина Да вот сейчас
remembered
вспоминал
Montenegro  We talk mostly about
черногори я в основном о спорте мы
sports in sports Why were there no
на спорте Почему на Олимпиаде не было
Russian athletes at the Olympics? I didn’t see something
российских спортсменов не видел я что-то
on
по
TV Well, why? Because
телевизору Ну как почему Потому что
sanctions were imposed against them for aggression, that’s
санкции вели против них за агрессию это
the very thing.
самое А почему вели
Why were they imposed? I mean, why were
В смысле почему ввели
sanctions introduced? Well, because of the war?
санкции Ну из-за войны что
something incomprehensible because of aggression I’m the same, but
непонятного-то из-за агрессии Я же го а
what kind of war is there, it’s not a war,
какая война то же нету сво есть не война
if there was a war, they would impose sanctions
если бы война была то вводили бы санкции
And so you
А так это
know, someone says that this is theirs,
сво понимаете кто-то говорит что это сво
someone says that this is a war, right there I  Well,
кто-то говорит что это война тут же я ж
not the International Olympic Committee,
не Международный олимпийский комитет
but do you think that this is a war or
а вы как считаете что это война или
listen to you? I think that this is still a
сво слушайте Я считаю что это всё-таки
war because, well, people are dying on both sides. I
война потому что ну с обоих сторон
understand who is to blame for this war. What do you think are the politicians? Well, what kind of
считаете политики полити Ну какие
politicians? Both of them
политики И те и те другие
mutual miles the names of these politicians
обоюдно мили фамилии этих политиков
Name
Назовите
Listen, I don’t know all the names, of course,
Слушайте я всех фамилий конечно не знаю
not all of them are a few Name the guy there there is a
не всех несколько Назовите чка там там
person there twenty and ten five
человек там двадцатку с десяте пятку
Name the five of these politicians who are
Назовите пятёрку этих политиков кто
to blame for this
виноват в этой
war So let’s start with the five Okay
войне Так давайте с пятёрки начнём
so the five will be headed by Zhezin of course
Окей так пятёрку возглавят конечно жезин
or anyone  the president decides they are like
ни кто-то решает президент они как
Puppets, damn it’s difficult, you put me right in the
Марионетки блин сложно вы меня прямо в
corner Well, let’s
угол поставили Ну давайте Давайте
try to find if these
попробуем найти если эти
presidents name the presidents there of
президенты назвать президентов там
Russia Ukraine there America there it’s not
России Украины там Америки там это нет
that’s not a problem No, come on Let’s
это же не проблемно Нет ну давай Давайте
try to find The
попробуем найти Элита
other Elite What kind of Elite made who the heel of
другая Что за Элита заставила кто пятка
these  the people who forced Tina
этих людей которые заставили Тина
have five no wait Putin's heel Putin's
у пятёрка нет подождите пятка Путина
five Putin's big five Putin's
пятёрка Путина великоб пятёрка Путина
new series for Tarantino No, it's not
новый сериал для Тарантино Да нет это не
that a little we think we think who the heel what
то немножко думаем думаем кто пятка что
made Putin attack the
заставила Путина напасть на
Russian
у т российские
political
полити
inri set Putin to attack Ukraine
инри ставили Путина напасть на Украину
Nava I'll name my last name now I'll remember
наву назову сейчас фамилию вспомню
loser this now now now
м неудачника этого сейчас сейчас сейчас
now
сейчас
now who was humming that m
сейчас который напевал то м
damn it like now now now now
блин как сейчас сейчас сейчас
Naryshkin now
нарышкин
who was humming to Putin that they were
сечас который Путину напевал что о том
waiting for us there from the loaf
что нас там ждут с каравайка
that Yes Lord okay now I’ll remember
что Да Господи ладно сейчас вспомню по
during the conversation
ходу беседы
Let’s assistant to the president he was the
Давайте помощник президента он был
vice president he was also
вице-президентом он ещё был
Now he’s under house arrest, or
Сейчас он под домашним орестом сидит а
maybe he’s not sitting there anymore so you know him.
может и не сидит уже чтоб ты его
Well, okay, I’ll remember, I’ll say it from the
ладно я вспомню походу скажу из
Ukrainians. Well, that’s understood, let’s,
украинских Ну это понят давайте давайте
let’s help you,
давайте я вам помогу
su Surkov Surkov, God,
су Сурков Сурков так Боже всё помнил
damn it, I’m sorry, I’m sorry. Wow, Surkov
блин прошу прощения точно Ух Сурков
got it right. Finally, I thought  you can’t squeeze
угадал Наконец я думал вы не выдавите
it out like that
это так
super Surkov forced Putin to attack
супер Сурков заставил Путина напасть на
Ukraine, let’s say he was a curator,
Украину он скажем был так куратором
most likely a confidant of someone who
скорее всего доверенным лицом кото там
was involved in fraud there, he said that
занимался махинациями говорил что там
everything was fine there waiting for us Everything’s great So
нас ждут всё отлично Всё классно Так
wait, but he forced Putin who attacked
подожди но заставил Путина кто напасть
Ukraine or Putin himself took it after all
на Украину или Путин всё-таки сам принял
decision It is clear that the leader
решение Понятно руководитель
makes the decision himself but consults with his own
принимат решение сам но советуется своми
colleagues, not
какими-то коллегами не
colleagues, but again some factors compel him to do so,
коллегами но опять же заставляют его
factors are the behavior of other
сост факторы это поведение других
countries,
стран
relationships are acceptable, Well, Ukraine’s desire to
отношения допустим Ну желание Украины
join NATO Yes, it is clear that no one
вступить в НАТО Да понятно что никому
will like this,
понравится
but what if some neighbor  Russia joined
а если бы какой-то сосед России вступил
NATO Russia wouldn't like it No, I'll
НАТО России бы это не понравилось Нет я
continue, you'll forgive NATO, it was created
же продолжу вы простите НАТО оно создало
for a reason, in order to regulate,
для чего для того чтобы урегулировать
stop or hinder the Soviet
остановить или помешать там Советскому
Union there, so the Soviet Union is long gone, we've
Союзу так Советского Союза уже давно нет
forgotten about the scoop, we're eating up its remains,
уже забыли про совок доедаем его остатки
you can say
можно сказать
yes, but why then this  Why is there
да А зачем тогда вот это зачем там
any
вот Америка вобще
need for America to
согласитесь Украина зачем там Украине
join NATO? Why should Ukraine join NATO or Georgia or
вступать НАТО или там Грузии или там
another country? So it’s not America, it’s
другой стране Так это не амери это
Ukraine that
Украине нужно вступить в
needs to join NATO. No, I understand why they need all this because Ukraine wants to
всё это потому что хочет Украина хочет
join NATO to protect itself from  For Russia,
вступить НАТО чтобы защититься от России
that’s
вот и
all. But for some reason, let’s
всё А ели заа
allow
отчего допустим для остановления
Moscow’s aggression to stop Moscow’s aggression. Well,
агрессии Москвы агрессии Москвы Ну да
now Russia is essentially the successor of the
сейчас Россия по сути есть продолжателем
imperial policy of the Soviet Union, that’s
имперской политики Советского Союза вот
all; a successor, a successor, that is, not a
и всё приемник преемник то есть не
successor, but a continuator of
приемник но продолжатель политики
such a policy, well, in any country. I think it
такой ну любой стране Мне кажется
will be unpleasant when you  here on the
Неприятно будет когда у тебя вот на
border, especially from another continent,
границе тем более с другого континента
but it seems to me
ка вот мне каже
that Estonia Lithuania
что Эстония Литва уже давным-давно
joined NATO a long time ago Right on the border of Russia
вступили в НАТО Прямо на границе России
and why Russia liked it
и почему России это нравилось
Estonia Lithuania The Baltic states in general, they were
Эстония Литва Прибалтика вообще она
n’t particularly
особо-то и в Советском Союзе не особо
worried there in the Soviet Union, that is  they were one of the
там переживали да то есть они одни из
first, in my opinion, to leave, yes, yes, but they
первыми же по-моему вышли да да но они
joined NATO. Why Russia didn’t attack
вступили в НАТО Почему Россия не напала
them for this, I know. Well, I’m not Peskov. I’m
на них за это знаю Ну я ж не Песков Я же
not the president’s talking mustache. Well, you are
не говорящий усы президента Ну вот вы ты
now you are now talking mustache, you’re
сейчас ты сейчас говорящий усы ты
telling why Russia attacked
рассказываешь Почему Россия напала на
you didn’t move to Ukraine
ты не переходил
Let’s have a business reference,
Давайте делового приведения должна
don’t look at us, according to the rules of the
быть у нас не смотрите у нас по правилам
Ukrainian language, Russians are not
украинского языка россиян навы не
called navas and
называют и
that was officially
что официально
adopted Zelensky signed a decree Yes,
приняли Зеленский подписал указ Да что
according to the rules of Ukrainian etiquette, Russians
по правилам украинского этикета россиян
can only be called by their first name Toda and
можно называть только на ты Тода с
Minin can’t break the laws
Минин не могу нарушать законы своей
look at your country You live in a
страны вам смотрите Вы живёте в
free country You can say
свободной стране Вы можете говорить что
anything Yes me if I speak to Russians
угодно Да меня если я буду с россиянами
in You yes you take Write it down,
говорить на Вы да вы возьмёте Запишите
put it on the Internet and the
выложите потом в интернет и ко мне
language patrol will come to me and say that you
придёт языковой патруль и скажешь что ты
respectfully communicated with a citizen of the
С уважением общался с гражданином страны
aggressor country and  everything Well, listen to me, too,
агрессора и всё Ну слушайте ко мне тоже
after this video. If you post it there
после этого видео Если вы выложите там
too, go there to the local police officer and say, That’s
тоже пойти Там участковый и сказать Вот
what you said there, I’ll at least answer for my
что ты там на говорил я-то хоть за свои
words. Well, here we have it. Well, you can’t.
слова отвечу Ну а у нас тут Ну нельзя У
We have a law, you can’t call a Russian a
нас есть закон нельзя называть россиянин
new person. That’s why you  I must accept this, this
новы Поэтому ты должен это принять это
tolerance must be poked, I don’t
толерантность должна быть тыкать мне не
need to, so that’s it. Well, according to the law,
нужно так что это само Ну ну по закону
according to the law of Ukraine, I have to communicate
по закону Украины я должен так общаться
with
с
you like this then. All the best. Well then, you’re
тобой тогда Всего доброго Ну тогда ты
going And you’re a nuclear bomb on Moscow and I’m
ид А вы ядерную бомбочку на Москву и Я
small That’s your whole essence Yes now  you
мал Вот ваша вся сущность Да теперь ты
understand Where you are going, yes, that’s your
понял Куда ты идёшь вот да вот в ва ваша
essence Yes, but
сущность Да а вот
yours,
ваша
come on, it’s not normal, I didn’t come up with this I’m an
давай не нормально это ж я не придумал Я
arrogant citizen, the
заносный гражданин
Verkhovna Rada signed such a decree, also
такой указ Верховная Рада подписала тоже
adopted such a law. Everything I have to do, I
приняла такой закон Всё я должен
can’t do it any other way.
исполнять не могу по-другому
Instagram  Instagram popk Andriy
мий Instagram попк Андрий вот
like this, let me check for you
так давай я тебя чекаю